<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Hi, John here</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Hi, John here</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extract weather and climate data from online repositories</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09-13-extract-weather-and-climate-data-from-online-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09-13-extract-weather-and-climate-data-from-online-repositories/</guid>
      <description>In a world experiencing climate change, good weather and climate data matters. It may be available but often hard to find, understand and apply to decision-making mainly because:
There are no weather stations everywhere Weather stations are not in good condition (gaps) The data is not stored correctly The data does not pass the basic quality controls Access to data is restricted However, weather and climate data products derived from satellites and model-based reanalysis have been used in locations where station based observations are inadequate or incomplete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map making with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-13-map-making-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-13-map-making-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Maps have been part of human history for a long time; representing the real world on paper and now via the web. The process should be simple, but it’s often challenging to non-GIS people.
Software such as ArcGIS and QGIS have made map making an easy process, while you will need a license to use the former, the latter is a free and open-source software (FOSS).
However, R - a statistical programming language has spatial capabilities that can be used for map making.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
